{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tippi Hedren","incorrectAnswers":["Barbara Stanwyck","Anne Bancroft","Meryl Streep"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Melanie Daniels in The Birds?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Vanir","incorrectAnswers":["Maiar","Frost Giants","Valhallans"],"question":"In Norse myth, there were two separate races of gods: the Aesir gods which included Odin and Thor, and the ____ gods from whom descended Freya.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Sierra Leone","Croatia","Seychelles"],"question":"Canberra is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Mongolia","Malaysia","Japan"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Delhi?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Gold","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Netherlands?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Uruguay","Peru","Bahamas"],"question":"In which country is the city of Curitiba?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Venezuela","Brazil","Colombia"],"question":"Buenos Aires is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dmitry Glukhovsky","incorrectAnswers":["Salman Rushdie","Agatha Christie","Stephenie Meyer"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Metro 2034'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'First Folio'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Filo ","incorrectAnswers":["Choux","Flaky","Short crust"],"question":"What type of pastry is usually bought frozen in wafer thin slices?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"After he becomes a quadriplegic, an aristocrat hires a young man to be his caregiver.","incorrectAnswers":["A naive youth leader is appointed to fill a vacancy in the U.S. Senate.","An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant.","When a serial killer murders key political figures, a vigilante is forced to intervene."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Untouchable?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Columbia","incorrectAnswers":["Challenger","Discovery","Endeavour"],"question":"Which space shuttle, commanded by John Young, was the first manned U.S. spacecraft to land on land on April 14, 1981?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jared Leto","incorrectAnswers":["Peter Cushing","Kenneth Branagh","Luke Evans"],"question":"Which actor has had roles in films including Fight Club and Requiem for a Dream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Barbados","incorrectAnswers":["Bahrain","Thailand","Benin"],"question":"Cou Cou and Flying Fish is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hey Diddle Diddle","incorrectAnswers":["Humpty Dumpty","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Baa Baa Black Sheep"],"question":"What nursery rhyme includes a cow jumping over the moon?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Kra–Dai","Niger–Congo","Austronesian"],"question":"The language 'Sudanese Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Argentinosaurus","incorrectAnswers":["Eodromaeus","Stegosaurus","Spinosaurus"],"question":"Which of the following is widely considered to be the largest dinosaur?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Finland","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Lithuania","Syria"],"question":"Which of these countries has blue on its flag?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I'll have what she's having.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Toga! Toga!\"","\"I’m just one stomach flu away from my goal weight.\"","\"Just keep swimming.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'When Harry Met Sally...'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Georgia","Peru","Malaysia"],"question":"Which country's flag can be described as 'Three equal horizontal bands of black red and gold.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels","incorrectAnswers":["La Haine","The Deer Hunter","Dead Poets Society"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'Eddy has a week to pay back £500,000 after losing a poker game to a powerful local mobster.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Scientist who contributed in fields of electromagnetism and electrochemistry.","incorrectAnswers":["Leader of US forces during American Revolution.","Inventor of the printing press.","Philosopher and mathematician who famously said “I think, therefore I am.”"],"question":"Which of the following describes Michael Faraday?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"William Morton","incorrectAnswers":["Mani","Edward Grace","John Locke"],"question":"Who was thr influential dentist who pioneered the use of anaesthetic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mikhail Bulgakov","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Ayn Rand","Stanisław Lem"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Heart of a Dog'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gwyneth Paltrow","incorrectAnswers":["Cate Blanchett","Fernanda Montenegro","Meryl Streep"],"question":"Who won the 1998 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Viola De Lesseps in Shakespeare in Love?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Doing Business As","incorrectAnswers":["Demanding Better Accountability","Direct Business Action","Digital Business Analytics"],"question":"What does the term 'D.B.A.' stand for in the legal industry?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Justin Timberlake","incorrectAnswers":["Usher","Bruno Mars","Ed Sheeran"],"question":"Which pop star won the Grammy Award for Best Male Pop Vocal Performance in 2007, with the song \"What Goes Around... Comes Around\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dien Bien Phu","incorrectAnswers":["Hue","Saigon","Phnom Penh"],"question":"In 1954, which Vietnamese village was the site of the decisive battle in the Indochina War, and caused the French to be defeated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Under the Bridge'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A French cuff","incorrectAnswers":["A button cuff","A barrel cuff","A saville cuff"],"question":"What is a wide cuff that is folded back and fastened with a cuff link called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Republic of the Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Gabon","Equatorial Guinea","Rwanda"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Central African Republic?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Bahamas","Mauritius","Albania"],"question":"Quito is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Football","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Tennis","Surfing"],"question":"With which sport is David Beckham associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Death before defeat","incorrectAnswers":["Seize the day","I came, I saw, I conquered","What is said is done"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Morior invictus' translate into English?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Riviera","incorrectAnswers":["The Promenade","The Mediterranean","The Coastline"],"question":"What name, meaning 'shore', today refers to the southeastern coastline of France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"One Thousand and One Nights","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte's Web","Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","The Snow Queen"],"question":"In which book does 'Scheherazade' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"William","incorrectAnswers":["Robert","Harold","Alfred"],"question":"Who was the first Norman King of England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I love lamp.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Rosebud.\"","\"You're gonna need a bigger boat.\"","\"Shane. Shane. Come back!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Anchorman: The Legend of Ron Burgundy'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2013","incorrectAnswers":["2011","2015","2017"],"question":"In which year was The Wolf of Wall Street first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1962","incorrectAnswers":["1950","1970","1973"],"question":"When did the Cuban Missile Crisis bring the world to the brink of nuclear war?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Suzanne Collins","incorrectAnswers":["Frederik Pohl","Dan Brown","Philip K. Dick"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hunger Games'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dead Poets Society","incorrectAnswers":["Raging Bull","Modern Times","The Wizard of Oz"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A maverick teacher emboldens his students to new heights of self-expression.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hadrian's Wall","incorrectAnswers":["Caesar's Wall","Julius' Wall","Octavian's Wall"],"question":"Which wall did the Romans build to keep out marauding Scots?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the Soviet Union","incorrectAnswers":["interactions between organisms and geomorphological processes","the study and design of machines at the molecular level","the structure of diseased tissues"],"question":"What is Kremlinology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Charlton Heston","incorrectAnswers":["Dwayne Johnson","Shah Rukh Khan","Gérard Depardieu"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Ben-Hur and The Ten Commandments?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1799","incorrectAnswers":["1899","1699","1999"],"question":"In what year did Napoleon first become ruler of France?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"J.K. Simmons","incorrectAnswers":["Chris Evans","Chiwetel Ejiofor","Michael Douglas"],"question":"The role of J. Jonah Jameson in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"This is the day you will always remember as the day you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"I'll get you, my pretty, and your little dog, too!\"","\"Keep your friends close, but your enemies closer.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"DNR (do not resuscitate)","incorrectAnswers":["CPR (cardiopulmonary resuscitation)","ALS (advanced life support)","SOS (save our souls)"],"question":"What is the 3-letter order which, when given by a patient, calls for no chest compressions?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Siege of Vienna","incorrectAnswers":["The Battle of Ankara","The Battle of Marj Dabiq","The Siege of Istanbul"],"question":"What event marked the beginning of the decline of the Ottoman Empire?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Acidity Or Alkalinity","incorrectAnswers":["Radiation","Wind Speed","Gravity"],"question":"What Is PH A Measure Of","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2008","incorrectAnswers":["2006","2010","2012"],"question":"In which year was The Dark Knight first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Tchaikovsky","incorrectAnswers":["Handel","Bach","Schuberg"],"question":"Who was the composer of 'The Nutcracker' ballet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mont Blanc Tunnel","incorrectAnswers":["Italo-Franco Tunnel","Trans-Alpine Tunnel","Labinnah Tunnel"],"question":"What tunnel connects France and Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Russell Crowe","incorrectAnswers":["Seth Rogen","John Wayne","Ron Perlman"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in both A Beautiful Mind and Man of Steel?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Hungary","Israel","Russia"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Rani-ki-Vav?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Mother of mercy, is this the end of Rico?\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I wish I knew how to quit you.\"","\"May the odds ever be in your favor.\"","\"I love lamp.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Little Caesar'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Cameron","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Terminator 2: Judgment Day?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tom Hanks","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Day-Lewis","Laurence Fishburne","Anthony Hopkins"],"question":"Who won the 1993 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Andrew Beckett in Philadelphia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Amphibians","incorrectAnswers":["Mammals","Reptiles","Marsupials"],"question":"What are frogs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'About a Girl'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo and Juliette","Othello","King Lear"],"question":"Which Shakespeare play begins with 3 witches?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alexander Pushkin","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Leo Tolstoy","Henryk Sienkiewicz"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Queen of Spades'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1956","incorrectAnswers":["1940","1948","1964"],"question":"When did the Suez Crisis become a flashpoint in the Cold War?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mural","incorrectAnswers":["Sculpture","Graffiti","Mozaic"],"question":"A large painting or decoration done on a wall is known as what?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Steven Spielberg","incorrectAnswers":["Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese","Alfred Hitchcock"],"question":"Which director directed Raiders of the Lost Ark?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Deliverance","incorrectAnswers":["Cabin in the Woods","Night of the Living Dead","Saw"],"question":"What is the name of the 1972 film in which a canoe trip into the Georgia backwoods becomes a living nightmare for four friends?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Asia","incorrectAnswers":["Africa","South America","North America"],"question":"In which continent would you find the Yellow river?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Double Indemnity","incorrectAnswers":["Jaws","Network","Raiders of the Lost Ark"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Phyllis Dietrichson'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oslo","incorrectAnswers":["Bern","Ljubljana","Nicosia"],"question":"What is the capital city of Norway?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pop Muzik","incorrectAnswers":["No Rain","I'm Too Sexy","How Do You Talk to an Angel?"],"question":"What song did M have a hit with in 1979?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dancing","incorrectAnswers":["Buzzing","Singing","Whistling"],"question":"How does a scout bee communicate to other bees about the location of flowers?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tamil","incorrectAnswers":["Hindi","Bengali","Gujarati"],"question":"Which of these Indian languages falls into the \"Dravidian\" language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Virginia Wade","incorrectAnswers":["Heather Watson","Sue Barker","Annabel Croft"],"question":"As of 2021, Who is the last British player to win the women's singles title at Wimbledon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Their Eyes Were Watching God","incorrectAnswers":["The Wind in the Willows","The Maltese Falcon","The Member of the Wedding"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Janie Crawford'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North Africa ","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","Central America","Eastern Europe"],"question":"Where Are The Atlas Mountains?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Montezuma Cypress","incorrectAnswers":["Cortes Elm","Santana Cedar","Kahlo Pine"],"question":"What is the name of the Mexican national tree?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hagrid","incorrectAnswers":["Snape","Malfoy","Potter"],"question":"Rubeus is the first name of which character in the Harry Potter books?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mikhail Bulgakov","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Ayn Rand","Stanisław Lem"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The White Guard'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dante Alighieri","incorrectAnswers":["Giovanni Boccaccio","Agatha Christie","Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Divine Comedy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in disinfectants and antiseptics.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in nuclear reactors, as a neutron moderator.","It is used as oscillators in radios, watches.","It is used for surface purification, bleaching, odour removal and water disinfection."],"question":"What is the chemical isopropyl alcohol often used for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Suckers","incorrectAnswers":["Tentacles","Pads","Grippers"],"question":"What is the name of the organ used by an octopus to cling to surfaces?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"guru","incorrectAnswers":["swami","pope","rabbi"],"question":"Which term was first applied to Nanak, the founder of the Sikh faith?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Atlanta","incorrectAnswers":["Dallas","Houston","Columbus"],"question":"Which city was burned by General Sherman in 1864?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"American Football","incorrectAnswers":["Soccer","Baseball","Basketball"],"question":"What sport do the following terms belong to - \"Tight End & Wide Receiver\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Portugal","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Spain","France"],"question":"From which European country did Mozambique declare independence in 1975?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Scent of a Woman","incorrectAnswers":["The Godfather","Dirty Dancing","Scarface"],"question":"Which 1992 film featured Al Pacino as a blind character who could tango?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"California","incorrectAnswers":["Florida","Texas","Ohio"],"question":"1955 saw the first ever Disneyland open in which U.S. state?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ratatouille","incorrectAnswers":["Amélie","Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind","Aladdin"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A rat makes an unusual alliance with a young kitchen worker at a famous restaurant.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Uralic","Kra–Dai","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Mandarin Chinese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Rice ","incorrectAnswers":["Spinach","Paneer","Basa"],"question":"What Is The Principle Ingredient Of Biryani?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Good Will Hunting","incorrectAnswers":["The Bourne Identity","The Departed","Argo"],"question":"What film was co-written by Matt Damon and Ben Affleck?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Crystal Palace","incorrectAnswers":["Big Ben","St Paul's Cathedral","The Tower of London"],"question":"Which London building was gutted by fire in November 1936?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Africa","incorrectAnswers":["Norway","Malta","Iceland"],"question":"Which of these countries has black on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"360","incorrectAnswers":["1","100","3.14"],"question":"How many degrees are there in a circle?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which did Roger Waters co-found?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"All Star\" by Smash Mouth","incorrectAnswers":["\"I Will Always Love You\" by Whitney Houston","\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution","\"You're So Vain\" by Carly Simon"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Somebody once told me / The world is gonna roll me...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"John Slattery","incorrectAnswers":["Benedict Cumberbatch","Dave Bautista","Paul Bettany"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Howard Stark in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the album 'Violator'?","difficulty":"hard"},